# **Raphael Moita**

Phone: +48 574 093 208

E-mail: raphael.moita@gmail.com

Skype: raphaelmoita





linkedin.com/in/raphaelmoita github.com/raphaelmoita

#### **SUMMARY**

IT Professional, focused in software development, with 10+ years' experience working in worldwide companies. A fast learning, hands on and self-motivated professional. Currently acting as Sr Java Developer for cross-platform enterprise applications and integration solutions. Good experience on Web applications, multi threading, low latency and time response systems. Also act as Instructor on Java Training Courses.

#### **MAIN TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES**

- Experienced in Agile methodologies: Scrum and Kanban.
- Platforms Linux and Windows.
- Java 8
- Junit, Fitnesse
- Spark
- Spring Boot, Spring Core, Spring MVC, Spring Data.
- Bash shell.
- GIT,
- · Maven.
- Preferred IDEs: Eclipse and IntelliJ, sometimes Vim :)

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

# Java Developer at Luxoft (www.luxoft.com)

April 2017 - Present

Acting as a Java developer, in agile teams, working in the Forex back-end system, also reporting tool for Investment Banking and Wealth Management, and a forecasting system to calculate possible Forex market fluctuations.

#### Technologies:

Java8, Spring, Spark, JUnit, Mokito, Fitnesse, Intellij, Maven, GIT, Linux, Bash.

#### Java Developer at Banrisul (www.banrisul.com.br)

February 2011 - April 2017 (6 years 2 months)

Acting as a Java developer and Architect, in an agile team, mainly working on the Company's Java backend framework used by many internal systems. The framework was built from the scratch and today it is being used by more than 30 critical systems. Providing architectural support to internal teams on designing, developing and L1 production support. Also work as instructor on Java Training Courses.

# Technologies:

Java6/7/8, Eclipse, OSGI Plataform, JAssist, Java Mission Control, Java Flight Record, Visual VM, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (JQuery), Websocket, Oracle, DB2, Eclipse Plugin, Spring, RMI, JNA, JMX, SAX and StAX XML parsers, Junit, Linux, Bash scripts, Jenkins, Maven, CVS, SVN, Checkstyle.

# Java Developer Lead at ADP (www.adp.com)

November 2008 - December 2010 (2 years 2 months)

Worked as Developer Team Leader, on a agile environment, for the CMS ADP's Portal Team on three main releases, working closely with the Architecture team on code adapting, rewriting and data migrations.

#### Technologies:

Java6/7, Eclipse, Portlets, Websphere Portal, JSF, Jboss, Visual VM, HTML, CSS, JavaScript (Jquery, Dojo), Oracle, JMX, SAX XML parser, JUIT Professional, focused in software development, with 10+ years' experience workingnit, Hudson, CVS, SVN, Bladelogic.

#### **Developer at Dell** (www.dell.com)

December 2006 - November 2008 (2 years)

Worked as Sr. Java developer in a worldwide Java Standalone Client/ Server Swing Application that controlled the grades e promotions of the company.

#### Technologies:

Java6, Eclipse, Swing, Visual VM, HTML, JavaScript, Oracle, JMX, JUnit, SVN.

#### **Developer at Hewlett-Packard** (www.hp.com)

February 2006 - November 2006 (10 months)

Worked as Java developer on a Web Application which controlled some models of HP Servers for mission-critical environments (HP Integrity Servers).

#### Technologies:

Java6, Eclipse, JBoss, Tomcat, StrutsII, Axix WS, JMX, JUnit, EclEmma Code Coverge, SVN.

# **Developer at Vivo Inc.** (www.vivo.com.br)

January 2004 - February 2006 (2 years 2 months)

Worked as Java developer on Telecom Projects both Web and standalone applications.

#### Technologies:

JavaSE4/5, Eclipse, JBoss, Tomcat, Struts, CVS, Unix HP-UX, Linux, Oracle.

#### **COURSES AND CERTIFICATIONS**

- Sun Certified Programmer (SCJP) Sun
- Linux Advanced Linux Managment II Conectiva
- Dojo and WebSphere management eCore
- Spring Boot, String MVC udemy

# **LANGUAGES**

• English: Full Professional Proficiency

• Portuguese: Native

#### **EDUCATION**

- Master's degree, Information Tecnology
  PUCRS Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio Grande do Sul Mar 2002 - Oct 2006
- Bachelor's degree, System Analysis
  UCPEL Universidade Católica de Pelotas
  Jul 1997 Sept 2002